Look, I told you what happens
when the neck
don't break straight away
and they get strangled. Look.
He's got a stiffy.
Shh! You dirty boys.
Wait for it.
It's fucking Hanging Day!
Yeah!
Sinner!
Zillah!
Yeah!
Yes!
Sinners.
Come get your sinners.
Ha'penny for a sinner.
Keep up.
-You're hurting me.
-Come on!
You wanted to know
why he was hanged.
It's not my fault
men are disgusting.
Well, you shouldn't
have told me
no matter what I said.
Poor dolly.
Oh, I'm going to die.
If you are,
then be quick about it,
for I have things to do.
What a frightful racket.
Papa!
Oh, you look like a plate
of corned beef.
Have you been crying?
No. Only racing.
Racing?
If your mother were still here
she'd batter me
around the head
to see
how I've let you run wild.
She would not.
Oh, you didn't know her.
She was a terror.
She boxed for the county.
She had hands
like meat plates.
And her mustache was
as big and bristly as a broom.
No.
I expect
you shall have one too, Cathy,
since they run
in the maternal line.
Stop! You must not talk
about Mama like that.
And I shall not have
a mustache. I shall not!
Don't be tiresome, Cathy.
Nobody likes a sourpuss.
As well as a fright.
God's teeth, Nelly.
Can you do something
about her?
That's what you're here for.
Yes, sir.
And tell Mrs. Burton
I shall dine at The Ram.
Oh, do not go, Papa. Please!
I shall go because the company
is much better at The Ram
and there is considerably
less weeping.
Now then,
where's my fucking horse?
I'll warn the maids.
Papa! I'm sorry! Papa!
Get up! Get a move on!
See it were hotpot
at The Ram again, Zillah.
I'm amazed
he managed to eat anything.
Oh. He's pissed up the wall
again, Mrs. Burton.
Right.
You know what that means.
Check his britches
for soiling.
That poor little girl.
And what of that thing
he brought home, eh?
It's hiding somewhere.
But what's it doing here?
Mr. Earnshaw had
one of his fits of charity.
Oh, Lord. Then pray
for that little sod too.
Hello?
What are you--
And I said,
"This is not Liverpool,
this is not Bristol.
You cannot kick a child
in the street."
And the poor
wretch's father...
Well, it's probably
his father...
Anyway, the man said,
"Well, you take
the little devil then
if you're so worried."
And I said,
"Well, I shall! I shall!"
And here we are.
I was only asking
how long it is
you intend us to feed
and clothe him, sir.
As it will affect
the household purse.
I intend him to be clothed
and fed
for as long as I intend it!
Why must I be surrounded
by women?
Spend my days being endlessly
badgered and sniped.
Papa!
Oh, here's another hellcat
sent to torment me.
Oh, there is not a better
father in all the world.
Nor a better man.
Oh, so you like
your new friend, do you?
Very much, Papa.
Very, very much.
Although I do not think
he can talk,
therefore cannot give me
his name.
So I've called him Heathcliff,
after my dead brother.
Heathcliff...
Heathcliff, come here,
my dear boy.
Come, come, come.
You are most heartily
welcome here.
- Oh!
Can I dress him up?
Yes, of course.
He shall be your pet.
I shall be very, very kind.
Unless you're bad,
and then I shall pinch you.
Die, die, die!
Kill that rat!
Get him in the eye.
Get him in the eye. Go on!
Nice for her to have a friend.
A real friend, I mean.
Not a paid one.
Companions aren't paid.
Companions are ladies, Zillah.
Just because
your father was a lord
doesn't make you a lady.
Bastards can't be ladies,
Miss Nelly.
No matter
how much their father paid
to have them hidden away.
"Puh...
Puh-on-e-yuh. Puh-on"...
Po-ny. The pony.
"The pony"...
"The pony a... a-tuh-eh"...
Ate! The pony ate!
The pony ate the grass.
There's a picture, Heathcliff.
There's a picture of it, look!
Honestly, I shall have to make
you a paper cone
and call you a dunce.
And if you do,
I'll throw you out the window
and let the birds peck
at your eyes!
I'm not doing it anymore.
I don't wanna read!
- Temper, temper.
- Shut up.
Sorry.
Sorry, Heathcliff.
Do you want to try again?
I'll be more patient,
- I promise.
- No.
Well, then you shall
never read and never advance
and be very stupid forever!
-Go away.
-No.
-Just go away!
-Go away!
-No!
I won't go away.
I'll never go away.
I will never leave you
no matter what you do.
Walk up. That's it.
Cathy, can I come?
No, no, you wouldn't like it.
You're far too sensible.
Come on. She might follow us.
I'm the queen of the castle,
and you're the dirty rascal.
We need to go.
The rain will give over soon.
Your father will be very angry
if we're late. Please.
Stop worrying. It will
give over. I promise it will.
Yeah, but the sky
is black, Cathy.
No, no, no, no. You see there?
Blue.
But that's not enough blue
to get us back.
It is. You'll see. For blue
is blue, no matter how small.
Where have you been?
I said, where have you been?
We were caught
in a storm, Papa.
It is my birthday, Catherine,
and you have kept me waiting.
I believe you do not care
for me at all.
Of course I do, Papa. You're
the best father in the world.
I am so sorry.
You shall be sorry
when it's your own birthday
and I forget it.
Let's have supper
and celebrate properly.
It's cold.
Papa.
It's my fault, sir.
Not Cathy's. She wanted to
turn back but I ignored her.
Heathcliff, please.
All she has spoken of all day
is you and your birthday.
-Is this true?
-No.
I swear it. She's not
to blame.
Are you trembling?
Stop at once. You make me feel
like a brute. Stop it, I say.
Papa, please.
It was not his fault.
I feed you, and clothe you,
and save you
from poverty and despair.
I am the kindest man alive,
and you dare to tremble at me.
I'll give you something
to tremble about!
-Take her, Nelly! Take her!
-Papa, no! No!
-No, no! Get off me! No! No!
-Come here, you dog!
Go!
- Heathcliff! No!
- Come here!
No! No, no, no!
Hold still!
Hold still, you dog!
No! Heathcliff.
You dog. Bark!
Heathcliff.
What's he done?
Oh, you're bleeding.
Heathcliff, why did you lie?
It was my fault we were late.
Not yours.
I couldn't see him hurt you.
But this hurts me.
Don't you understand?
Heathcliff, this hurts me.
I will take this and more...
every day...
if it spares you.
Heathcliff...
Yes?
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Don't ever be sorry
for me, Cathy.
For I would do it
again and again.
Then we're doomed.
What can I do?
Nothing.
Just stay with me.
Heathcliff.
Answer me, you brute.
Are you awake?
No.
-Now?
-Catherine!
I was up all night
with the horse.
What could be so important?
Thrushcross Grange is sold.
We have neighbors.
They are called Linton.
- A family?
- A bachelor and his ward.
He made his fortune
in textiles.
God. Look at it all.
He must be very rich indeed.
I suppose he shall
fall in love with me.
fall in love with--
I heard you.
It would be nice to be rich.
What should you do,
Heathcliff?
-What?
-If you were rich.
I suppose I'd do
what all rich men do. I'd...
live in a big house.
And be cruel to my servants.
Take a wife.
A wife? What wife?
I... I've always
looked fondly on...
Rose from The Crown.
The landlord's daughter.
She's quite the plainest girl
I ever laid eyes on.
And dull too. Shockingly dull.
She's practically a simpleton.
I cannot sit here all day
talking nonsense with you.
After all, the Lintons may
call on me at any moment.
I warn you,
if they do not come soon,
I shall feel snubbed.
And you will have
a quarrel with them
before you have even met.
That would be a feat
even for you.
We are
a very important family.
Perhaps they do not know.
Earnshaws have been here
since 1500.
It is written above our door!
Why do they not come?
It has only been a week.
In fact, we're likely
far superior
to Mr. Linton's family,
who, after all,
made their fortune in velvet.
It is not at all the same
thing as land. Not at all.
Perhaps they're waiting
for me to call on them.
No.
Why not?
Because a lady cannot go
to a house unannounced.
It is not done.
They would be shocked.
They would not.
They would be delighted.
As are all who have
the pleasure
of making my acquaintance.
Perhaps that is
why they have not come.
They may be intimidated,
poor things.
Yes, I'm sure that's it.
Work on your tapestry.
I hate my tapestry.
I was not bored
before they came.
Now I'm so bored I might die.
What're you-- Heathcliff!
How dare you!
I have had enough
of hearing about Mr. Linton.
Heathcliff, I... I cannot
get down in these skirts.
Well, then you'll have to
take 'em off.
You will be so very sorry
when I fall out of this tree
and die!
Help!
Are you pleased with yourself?
Very.
Get off! It was just
a loose pebble.
Give me my hat, woman.
Arsehole.
Careful, sir.
Let's get you
on that horse, sir. Come on.
That's it. Steady.
Get off me.
I know how to ride a horse.
Fuck off, you silly woman.
Careful as you go,
Mr. Earnshaw.
Oh, Heathcliff.
Oh.
I-I fear we had
a run-in the other day.
What did I do?
Oh, don't tell me.
I can't bear it.
Ah, what a wretch I am.
Can you forgive poor Earnshaw?
Yes, sir.
Oh, splendid.
Splendid, boy. Yes.
I knew it couldn't be
as bad as I'd imagined.
Well, I'm off to town
to see if I can't find
that wretched solicitor.
For I know it's he who has
been spending all my money.
What happened the other day?
Nothing much. He just gave me
a cuff around the ear, is all.
Silly old fool.
He must know you could knock
his eyes out if you cared to.
He knows I don't care to.
Well, I wish you would.
Do you?
My only restraint is you.
Then you must be better
for both of us.
- Are you cold, Cath?
- Yes.
Let me make you a fire.
No. Papa will whip you
if you do.
We cannot spare the wood.
Hmm. He can always spare
the wood when he's cold.
He'll not need it tonight.
For his face
has made acquaintance
with the parlor floor.
-Again.
-Hmm.
It did not go well with the
solicitor.
We are ruined, Heathcliff.
There is nothing left.
He's gambled it all away.
I suppose I shall have
to throw myself
at Mr. Linton after all.
Hopefully I'll die of cold
and be spared the shame of it.
Heathcliff!
Do not throw yourself
at Mr. Linton, Cath.
Harder.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Must you do that here, Joseph?
The drain in the yard
is at overflow.
So my skirts
will be nothing but pig scab.
Every moment that passes,
we slide further and further
beyond the pale.
Sorry, Miss Catherine.
"Two households,
both alike in dignity
In fair Verona,
where we lay our scene."
And thus begins the greatest,
most romantic play
I have ever read
in my entire life.
And that is including Othello ,
which you know I loved, Edgar.
I actually believe
that the nurse is the villain
of the story
because she allows
this chaos to ensue,
knowing that they're going
to be doomed
and that there's going to be
so much death.
But I don't really like
the nurse actually.
But anyway, Mercutio
gets killed in the street.
Mercutio.
And Romeo then kills Tybalt
for revenge
for Mercutio's death.
He's murdered in the street.
And everyone sees.
So, Romeo,
he's banished from Verona.
And Juliet gets word of this,
and she's
absolutely devastated.
So she hatches this plan
with Friar Laurence, you see,
and-and she's going to take
this sleeping drink,
and she's going to elope
and no one's going to know.
And word of this
was supposed to be sent
to Romeo,
so that's where
you-you think it's gonna go.
But someone tells Romeo
that Juliet's dead.
But you see,
Juliet is not dead at all.
-She's only taken...
-No.
...a sleeping draft,
but Romeo did not know,
for he was in Mantua,
and the letters
had not reached him.
What a thorough précis,
Isabella.
I feel quite transported.
Oh, how I cried.
Edgar, I thought
my head might fall off.
Oh, dear.
That would not do.
Well, no, indeed not.
For then I should have nowhere
to put my ribbons.
Edgar!
-What on earth is it? What--
-Edgar, I saw a ghost.
Edgar, I saw a ghost.
I saw a ghost there.
There. By the wall.
Oh, Edgar, it had
the most fearsome visage.
Ghastly pale. It was hideous.
It had dead, evil eyes.
There will be some reasonable
explanation. Let me look.
Edgar, please don't leave me.
Please.
You are quite safe,
I assure you.
May I assist you?
"Have sprained
my ankle on a hideous wall.
Linton has taken me in."
Linton!
"Had cream cake for tea
and chocolate."
Chocolate?
She has underlined chocolate.
Clever little cat.
She'll be in clover.
But she's sprained her ankle.
I will go. I can carry her.
- 'Tis five miles.
- It's nothing.
No, no, no, no, no.
You can't go up there,
you silly boy.
You're a servant, Heathcliff.
This is her chance.
And likely her only one.
Well, she's already
well past spinsterhood.
We can't have you
blundering up there.
Would ruin her prospects.
Do... Nelly, we can't just...
A most impressive fellow,
you know.
A gentleman
through and through.
I mean, he's not quite out of
the top drawer, you know.
Obviously.
But we can overlook
such things, can't we?
As we have done with you,
my dear.
Oh, and the Grange.
You've never seen
anything like it.
The drawing room
is made of crystal.
How is Cathy?
Purring like a kitten.
Waited on hand and foot
by both Linton and his ward.
And what is she like?
- Miss Isabella?
- Yes.
Oh, she's very fine.
Very pretty indeed.
Good.
It is a wonder that Linton
didn't marry her himself.
But still,
I suppose they're more like
brother and sister really.
- When will Cathy be back?
- Soon enough.
She kept that ankle clamped
to a velvet pillow
for as long as is
remotely credible.
Mind you, if Linton is even
half as smitten as he looks,
I doubt
if she'll be back here long.
Whoa!
Oh.
Ooh, my poor boots.
Thank you, Joseph.
-Cathy.
-Miss Earnshaw.
What is it?
You are transformed.
It is all Isabella.
She is
the sweetest person alive.
She fixed my hair herself.
It is her special talent.
You know, she has a room
entirely for ribbons.
Just ribbons.
Where is Heathcliff?
Well, here you are.
You're back then.
Oh, is that it?
I've been gone six weeks.
You do not bother yourself
to greet me?
In fact,
I do believe you are hiding.
Oh, how cross you look.
And dirty.
I can smell you from here.
No one could be in any danger
of smelling you.
Just enough perfume
to make the eyes water.
It is lily of the valley.
It is no such thing.
You're angry because
I was gone for so long.
It could not be helped.
I'm not angry, Cathy.
I'm busy.
All right? You came to see me,
lo, here we are, so you have.
Why don't you go and bother
one of the other servants?
Heathcliff, do not--
For God's sake,
will you listen?
I tell you, I have work to do.
I cannot endlessly indulge
every last
wretched whim of yours.
We're not children
anymore, Cathy.
Surely you understand
that now?
I cannot play with you.
As though I could crave
your company
after so many weeks
with Edgar and Isabella.
Carry on with your work.
- Heathcliff, I want--
- You get in there.
Do you hear me?
Come on. Get in there.
Go.
You've been a bad girl.
A very bad girl.
You're not gonna be laughing
in a minute.
Where do you think you're
going, hey? Get back here.
You don't wanna stay here
with me? Stay with Joseph?
Hmm?
What do you want?
This'n, or...
Hmm?
Oh, yeah.
Ooh, fucking hell.
-Pull it harder, Joseph.
-I'll break your teeth.
Pull it harder.
Shh.
Oh, good girl.
Good girl.
You're amazin'.
-Cath...
-No.
Are you feeling quite right?
What? Oh, yes. Fine.
I'm going for a walk.
In those skirts?
Cathy!
- Cathy.
- Oh, God.
-Cath. Cath, it's nothing.
-No. Please go away.
-Go away and leave me alone.
-It's nothing.
Oh, God. Oh, God, I will die.
Don't die.
It's not worth dying over.
How dare you laugh at me,
you devil? This is your doing!
How is it my doing?
-Stop talking.
-Cath.
Stop. Do not talk to me
or look at me.
You're going to
make yourself ill.
Do not ever look at me again!
Stop or you will kill me.
Do not.
Do not. Let go of my hand.
Never.
I have you now.
I can follow you like a dog
to the end of the world.
Put me down.
If you care for me at all,
put me down.
Do not follow me.
I beg of you.
Come on, sir.
For God's sake...
Hold me up.
Don't look at me like that!
I'm ill!
We are all ill.
We are all ill because of you!
Ingrate! Slattern!
-Cathy...
-Not now, Nelly.
-Catherine...
-Not now, Nelly!
Whatever it is, it must...
Mr. Linton is in the parlor.
Mr. Linton?
Mr. Linton.
I am not fit to receive you.
Miss Earnshaw,
that could never be true.
Indeed it is. I... I fear
I must excuse myself.
Must be most distressing
to see your father so...
unwell.
You saw him then.
It is too shaming.
No.
It is all too shaming.
No, no.
I'm sorry, Mr. Linton.
I'm very sorry.
Miss Earnshaw, please, sit.
There is something I must say.
Please.
If I were in heaven, Nelly,
I should be
extremely miserable.
Because you're not fit
to go there.
Not just that.
It is because
I should be homesick.
Did something pass
between you and Mr. Linton?
He asked me to marry him.
And what was your response?
I accepted him.
Well, be quick, Nelly.
Tell me, was I wrong?
Do you love him?
One could not help
but love Edgar.
Then where is the obstacle?
Here.
In whichever place
the soul lives,
I'm convinced I am wrong.
Why?
Nelly, you know why.
Heathcliff.
I love him.
Not because he's handsome,
Nelly, but because he's...
more myself than I am.
Whatever our souls
are made of,
his and mine are the same.
Do not sigh at me.
I know you think
I'm a selfish wretch...
but if I marry Mr. Linton,
I could aid Heathcliff
to rise.
I could place him
out of my father's power.
With your husband's money?
You'll find him not so pliable
as you calculate upon.
Why did I ask you?
What would you know about it?
You've never loved anyone
in your whole life.
No one has ever loved you.
You say you love Edgar Linton.
You have accepted
his proposal.
It is done, Cathy.
I do not know what it is
you want from me.
Reassurance?
Compassion?
Some kindness?
You must know, Nelly, you.
It would degrade me
to marry Heathcliff.
We would be beggars.
So he shall never know
how I love him.
Where are you going?
To the Grange to call it off.
I could not sleep last night.
I should never
have accepted Linton.
Cathy, stop!
-Stop!
-What?
Joseph, tell her.
I'm sorry, Miss Earnshaw.
He made off with the horse.
Last night.
Cathy...
I do not think
he is coming back.
Of course he is.
He is only trying to vex me.
You know what he's like.
He would never
leave me, Nelly.
Never.
Did he come?
We could put it off.
It has been a year. It cannot
be put off any longer.
Tighter.
-Tighter.
-This is tight enough.
-Tighter, Nelly.
-But you will not breathe.
Tighter.
God, how I love you.
Cathy. Hello!
Can I give you
your wedding present now?
Oh, it's... it's quite lovely.
I made it the night
that Edgar proposed,
once I knew that you
would join us here forever.
-Is this?
-Your real hair. Yes.
For I had been collecting it
from the brush
while you stayed with us.
I... I knew I could not use
anything else,
for your hair is so singular.
Well, this... must have taken
a very long time.
Oh, no matter.
For I have nothing to do.
Let us put
Little Catherine here.
Oh, next to me.
How extraordinary.
Wait till you see
your dresses, Cathy.
Oh, Edgar.
How many did you have made?
This was all my dear ward.
Isabella knows everything.
She had all of these ordered.
From France
and Belgium and Italy.
All of the ateliers have been
making things
to your measurements.
I had to sacrifice
my ribbon room for it.
Oh, Isabella, no.
It was no hardship...
knowing how pleased
you would be.
Come. Come, there is more.
Oh, Cathy, wait till you see.
Your bedroom. When they asked
me what color it should be,
I said it should be the most
beautiful color in the world.
The color of my wife's
sweet face.
Here, look.
The freckle from your cheek.
Nelly.
-Nelly!
-Yes, Cathy.
Well, you have been quiet.
Quiet?
Since we came.
It is not like you
to be so silent.
Do you disapprove?
Of what?
I don't know.
Perhaps it is
only contentment.
You have no complaints?
What could there be
to complain about?
That we are too comfortable?
Too warm?
That your necklace is too big?
That the dog is too small?
It is too small.
I'll grant you that.
As for the rest?
This is good.
It is good, Cathy.
Hmm?
Everything all right, my love?
Catherine.
I'm fine.
Darling, what are you doing?
Gosh.
They said the
colors would be periwinkle.
- Please, Edgar!
- Bella.
But, Edgar, I'm grown up.
I'm 21 and a half.
Your age has
nothing to do with it, Bella.
Please.
You've been asking me
for weeks,
and for weeks I have said no.
Yes, but you
have not said why, Edgar.
- Absolutely not.
- Oh, please, Edgar! Please!
Do not press me, Bella.
A hanging is not
an appropriate place
for a young lady.
You are so old-fashioned.
Tell him, Catherine.
No, he is right.
You would not like it,
Isabella.
Indeed. Thank you, darling.
I've always found them
quite... barbaric.
- Hmm.
- That is a shame.
For I thought you
would have taken
a particular interest
in this hanging, Catherine.
Why?
Because of who
is being hanged.
What?
It is a woman.
Do you think
they will do it in her skirts?
Oh, for God's sake.
It would be quite indecent,
for surely one could only
look up and see--
Isabella, enough.
Look, you have upset
dear Catherine.
No, no.
I only need some air.
Mrs. Linton. Mrs. Linton.
Oh, Joseph.
Oh, it is good to see you.
-Yeah.
-It has been such a long time.
How are you?
How is Zillah?
Zillah? Gone. Married.
Oh.
Yeah, she's got a little...
a little boy now.
Tubby little rascal.
See them
in the village sometimes.
-She doesn't greet me.
-Oh.
But it wouldn't look well, her
talking to someone like me.
I know that.
I'd embarrass her.
No. I don't think that's true.
Have you come
to see your father?
How is he?
Hello, Daughter.
-Papa.
-Oh.
"Papa" is it now?
What has happened?
Uh, Zillah is gone,
and I've no money
to replace her.
And so, uh, we sink into ruin.
Edgar sends money, Papa.
I know he does.
Have you come here
to scold me?
Uh, no, I...
I came to wish you
a happy Christmas.
And to see how you are.
And how do you find me?
Quite well.
Not dead, you mean.
- You do look well, however.
- Mmm.
Gladdens my heart
to see you so happy, Catkin.
Perhaps you might share
some of that happiness
with your poor,
lonely, old papa.
Just give him a little bit
more to get by on.
You know I cannot, Papa.
For you will only
gamble it away.
And what will you
spend it on, eh?
More garish jewels?
More tawdry geegaws
to dangle about your person?
Well, I suppose
I should not begrudge it.
You've had no children
and nothing to do except
make yourself ridiculous.
No children
in all these years.
That fine husband of yours
not up to it, I suppose.
-Or perhaps it's you--
-Stop!
-There!
-No!
Since you will toss
your coins on the floor,
you will stay
and watch me grope for them,
since that is what
you meant by it.
I'm sorry.
Catherine. Catherine.
It's all right.
You're a very brave,
very good girl, my darling.
You have survived
that wretched place.
You need never
go back there again.
I do not know why I went back.
There is nothing for me there.
Oh, my.
Oh, look at this.
Happy Christmas, Nelly, dear.
Thank you, Cathy.
Oh.
A book of friendship.
Oh. Oh, you drew that?
Yes. Yes. That is you and I.
Oh. Ribbons.
That is
your beautiful silhouette
that I watched one day
from your room.
-Oh, look at this.
-What on Earth is that?
Yes, this is, um, a rose
which reminded me of you also.
The most beautiful rose
in the world.
- Beautiful.
- Oh.
Remember the day
that we went walking,
and you picked out
a mushroom and you said,
-"What a lovely mushroom"?
-Yes.
Well, I commemorated it
in decoupage.
God.
It's fantastic news,
Catherine.
All round.
It's fantastic news.
I have never been happier.
So you are excited
to become a father then?
I am giddy.
I feel like a chit fresh out
of the schoolroom.
You clever thing.
Will you stay here tonight?
Nothing would please me more.
But you need your rest,
my love.
And you will not rest
if I stay here with you.
Good night.
Good night, my love.
How wonderful.
Heathcliff.
Oh, what a wicked trick!
I dared not hope.
Let me look at you.
Oh, you are handsome.
You brute.
And rich.
Does that amuse you?
Not in the least.
Come. We must not
get the mopes.
Come to dinner.
Everyone will be
so delighted to see you.
I ruined my dress
climbing up there
to get to him,
and he did not move an inch.
So you have been abroad?
Oh, Edgar, look at him.
Of course he has.
Tell us, Heathcliff,
where have you been?
What have you been doing
these past years?
Was it very exciting?
At times.
Is that all? "At times"?
After near five years,
it was exciting "at times"?
Mmm.
I see you want me
to press it out of you.
Well, I will not beg you
for your story, Heathcliff.
In fact,
I am beginning to suspect
-that it was very boring.
-It wasn't.
Perhaps he was a pirate.
Perhaps I was.
Oh, dear. Surely not.
I really don't care
what you have been doing.
Do I, Edgar?
Darling, have I
even mentioned Heathcliff?
I do not believe so, my love.
You see?
Keep your secrets, Heathcliff.
And we will have to assume
that your fortune
was most ill-gotten.
Where are you staying?
At Wuthering Heights.
No, you... you mustn't.
The place is no more
than a ruin.
Tell him, Edgar.
He must come here.
-Indeed. If he... If...
-No.
No, I would rather be home.
Home? Yes, I suppose it is
a sort of home for you.
Yes, I should say so,
since I bought it.
You did not.
Oh, how wonderful.
For us to have a neighbor.
Wonderful.
He is the most handsome man
I ever saw.
Who is?
Mr. Heathcliff, of course.
Heathcliff?
He would devour you.
Oh! He would not.
He would indeed.
He is rough and wild
and of wicked temper.
Why would you say such things?
He is your friend.
Yes, it is because
he is my friend
that I can say it
with such certainty.
Oh, you are funny, Isabella.
He would crush you
like a sparrow's egg.
You are a dog
in the manger, Cathy!
Do you think I speak
from jealousy?
I only meant
to save you from humiliation.
By all means, pursue him.
I'm sure he'll find
your efforts greatly amusing.
As will I.
Oh, it will be some game.
For you two
have never quarreled.
What could there be
to quarrel about?
I'll be back by supper.
Goodbye, darling.
-Thank you.
-Sir.
I'm sure you know why Isabella
has savaged my poor doll.
It is because she is
quite besotted with you.
Hmm.
Indeed, I had not noticed.
You know she is.
But now that you bring it to
my attention, she is pretty.
-Heathcliff...
-And rich.
She's not been shy
about the inheritance
settled upon her
once she marries.
And she likes me, you say?
Why don't we ask her?
For I am quite certain
she's hovering by the door,
listening to us.
Isabella?
Isabella, come in, dear.
We know you are there.
Shall I come and fetch you?
Oh, look, Heathcliff.
Oh!
Someone who admires you
even more than I do.
Poor thing is breaking
her heart over you.
-Cathy, please.
-No! No, no, no.
-Excuse me.
-Don't run away, dearest.
Don't run away.
You see, Isabella thinks that
if only I would step aside,
she would shoot a shaft
of light into your soul
that would make you
a gentleman.
No!
Do not run.
I will not be named
a dog in the manger again.
I will go. You stay.
Have him to yourself.
Show him your dolls.
No.
You are a dog in the manger.
You have no interest in her.
You know you do not.
Leave her alone.
Why should I?
If it's kissing she wants,
I'm more than happy to oblige.
-You will not.
-I have a right to
if she chooses, and you have
no right to object.
I'm not your husband,
remember?
You have no right
to be jealous of me.
Do not scratch
at me, Heathcliff.
I have been nothing but kind
since your return.
No?
Have I chastised you once
for your desertion?
Have I delivered
a single rebuke?
These past years,
I have not known
if you were alive or dead.
And you dare to upbraid me?
When the fault is yours!
Mine?
-How have I wronged you?
-How?
You knew I loved you,
and you disregarded it.
Don't say you did not.
You treated me infernally.
Do you hear?
Infernally.
And if you flatter yourself
that I don't perceive it,
then you are a fool.
And if you think a few
sweet words will console me,
then you are an idiot.
And if you fancy
that you can
marry Linton unrevenged,
I will convince you
of the contrary.
Oh, there can be no peace
between us, Catherine.
I was a fool
to think otherwise.
For peace with you
is worse than war.
So, thank you
for telling me
Miss Isabella's secret.
I swear I'll make
the most of it.
For you are welcome
to torture me to death
for your own amusement.
Only please allow me to amuse
myself in the same style.
Kiss her then.
Marry her, for all I care.
It is nothing to me.
If I thought
you really meant that,
I'd cut my own throat.
So cut it.
Only do not do it
on this carpet.
For it is Edgar's favorite,
and he would be very sorry
to see it ruined.
I do not think
we should receive
Mr. Heathcliff anymore.
Whatever you wish, my dear.
Hmm.
Poor little Heathcliff.
I'm in no mood
for you tonight.
Oh, I just thought you might
like a little company.
There is gin
on the side table.
Let that be your companion.
Oh? Oh, thank you, dear boy.
You are good
to your old papa, aren't you?
It's a grim joke, my boy.
Is it not?
My dream in bringing you here
was to make
a gentleman of you.
Uh, and now, to look at us...
...who could tell
which was which?
Mmm.
It still is...
It's not enough, is it?
Not for her.
You're still just her pet.
You'll only ever be her pet.
Joseph?
Catherine.
-Is he in there? Is he? Is he?
-Don't.
I'm sorry, Papa. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Cath...
Please. Please.
Cathy!
-Cath.
-Do not follow me.
Wait.
Leave me alone.
-Cath!
-Leave me alone.
You're wet.
I am not.
-You're cold.
-I am not!
You will catch your death.
It will be your fault.
It will be yours!
No! No! Put me down!
You must put me down!
Do not hit me.
I only mean to keep you dry,
you wretched shrew.
I hate you.
What are you doing? Do not...
I should not have kicked him.
That was bad.
I can only admire
your restraint
in limiting it to twice.
The rain will not last, Cath.
There is some blue yet.
You and I both know
there is none.
Why did you leave me?
I thought it would kill me,
Heathcliff.
Why did you do it?
Why did I leave you?
Why did you despise me?
Why did you betray
your own heart?
Oh, I heard you that day,
the day you accepted Edgar.
You said it would degrade you
to marry me.
No, I... No.
No, Heathcliff, I...
You did not hear all.
I said that I loved you.
I love you.
You loved me? You loved me?
Then what right had you
to leave me?
Answer me. What right?
Oh, for the poor fancy
you felt for Linton?
Because misery,
degradation, death,
nothing that God or Satan
could inflict
would have parted us.
You did it, of your own will.
I have not broken your heart.
You have broken it.
And in breaking it,
you've broken mine.
So kiss me again.
And let us both be damned.
"Come unto me,
all ye that labor
and are heavy laden,
and I will give you rest.
Take my yoke upon you,
and learn of me;
for I am meek
and lowly in heart:
and ye shall find rest
unto your souls.
For my yoke is easy
and my burden is light."
Cathy.
-Catherine.
-Hmm?
You will be careful,
won't you?
Does Heathcliff know?
I do not know what you mean.
That you are with child.
No.
I love you.
Quick. Be quick. Quick.
I know.
This cannot go on.
Who says so?
My conscience.
Then do not listen.
You are not married.
You cannot feel the flames
at your feet.
Well, at least now
your feet are warm, Cath.
Do not jest.
Do not.
Heathcliff, do not...
I hate you.
Well, I love you.
Go.
Very well.
Tomorrow?
I thought we must stop?
I have to go.
- No.
- Yes.
Cath? Cath, what is it?
Nothing. Only I am so happy.
-I love you.
-Don't say it.
I love you.
You'll kill me.
-I love you.
-Don't say it.
-I love you. I love you.
Why do you stay here?
It's filthy. Why don't you
stay in my old room?
Because then I cannot lie here
as I do now.
And imagine that
we are still children.
And you're asleep
in your bed across the yard.
And there is still a chance.
I wish I had never said it.
I changed my mind immediately.
I was going to call it off
the next day.
If I had known
you were listening...
I always thought you did.
How could I?
Because Nelly saw me.
You will find
another position, Nelly.
What?
You will find
another position.
-Another position?
-Immediately.
What is it you suspect me of?
Treason.
What treason?
The night that Heathcliff
disappeared,
he was listening to us.
He heard. And you knew.
And you did not tell me
that he was there.
You did not give me
the opportunity to rectify
what would become
the worst mistake of my life.
Why?
Why, Nelly?
Do you know what I think?
I think you like
to see me cry.
Not half as much
as you like crying.
You will tell Edgar
you have found a new place.
And you will go.
Where will I go?
I don't care.
Catherine.
Yes, darling?
I think it is best
that you do not see
Mr. Heathcliff anymore.
-But, darling, I...
-Don't.
You were quite right,
of course,
to welcome him here
while he found his feet.
But I think it's best we sever
the connection now, don't you?
It would be most distressing
if anyone mistook
your natural good-heartedness
for something untoward.
Especially given
your condition.
Of course.
You are right, as always.
Thank you, darling, for saving
me from my own foolishness.
What are you reading?
Oh, j-just s-some
silly nonsense.
What on earth was that?
The swallows get lost
when the wind changes.
-Let me see to it.
-Don't.
Please.
I don't want it to suffer.
If it will make you
feel better.
Where are you?
I know you are here.
Are you mad?
You've broken the window.
You have to go.
Where were you?
Heathcliff,
you do not understand.
Catherine,
is everything all right?
Yes, my love.
Well, come back inside.
He cannot see us.
- Are you sure?
- Do not--
No, no. You mustn't.
I mustn't?
Wasn't that your tongue
in my mouth, Cathy?
I'll set the dogs on you.
And every bite will be
a pleasure coming from you.
Enough.
Come on. Back inside.
Sorry, darling.
It's freezing.
You'll catch your death.
I like the cold.
Yes, but our son may not.
Tell me.
Is it mine?
It is not.
How can you be sure?
I was sure
before your return.
I'm sorry.
It is Edgar's child.
Did you think I would mind?
Did you think
it would stop me?
Indeed, I only would have
enjoyed it more.
You fiend.
I'm amazed he had it in him.
I'm amazed
he would dare touch you.
You would be shocked at
the things Edgar dares to do.
-Would I?
-It would make you blush.
Is that right?
It would make even Joseph
and Zillah blush,
what he does to me.
And that is how
you found yourself
in this squalid condition.
Yes.
I'm amazed
it didn't happen sooner.
He barely lets me sleep.
He cannot keep
his hands off me.
-He loves me so much.
-You liar.
He does. He loves me.
And you love him.
More than anything.
More than anyone.
I love him so.
I've never loved anyone else.
You bitch.
-This is how you love him?
-Yes.
-I'll kill him. Yeah.
-Oh, God, yes.
-I'll crush his ribs.
-Yes.
I'll tear his heart out.
I'll slit his throat.
I'll drink his fucking blood.
Would you really kill him?
I'll go to his room directly,
and I'll break his neck.
Tell me to do it.
Make me do it.
Oh, God.
I said that you
would degrade me.
I did not know
that I would degrade myself.
It's only a little shame,
Cath. It will not last.
Let me go.
Let me go, Heathcliff.
Listen to me.
This cannot go on.
Heathcliff, it is done.
You don't mean it.
It is done.
I love you.
It doesn't matter.
It is too late.
You are too late.
No.
I'll never forgive you.
Do you know how this works?
Would you like me to show you?
Cathy was right.
I am rough
and cruel
and cold and unfeeling.
Do you want me to stop?
I do not love you.
I will never love you.
I will treat you abominably.
Do you want me to stop?
I will marry you
with the sole purpose
of tormenting Catherine.
I will think of her
every moment I am with you.
Do you want me to stop?
No.
Isabella?
Is everything all right?
Ugh. Filthy creature.
Will you stop crying?
Come on.
I've married you, haven't I?
All I have to ask you is,
are you of marriageable age?
Yes.
-Are you free to marry?
-Yes.
She is a fool.
I can bear much, Catherine.
But I will not stand for you
weeping over that fiend
in front of me.
It is enough.
All right? Enough.
Are you free to marry?
Yes.
Congratulations. You may
kiss the bride, etcetera.
I'm so sorry.
-I cannot help it.
-You will, for God's sake.
You will help it.
Get out of my sight
until you're recovered.
This is indecent, Cathy.
Pull yourself together.
Dear Nelly,
I know that Edgar will not
accept a letter from me,
so I am come to you.
I cannot begin to describe
the trials
of this last fortnight.
I only wish to ask,
since you know my husband,
what have I married?
Is Mr. Heathcliff a man?
If so, is he mad?
If not, is he a devil?
I have no doubt that
he has me under some spell,
which I am incapable
of breaking.
Oh, s-sorry, sir.
Do not worry,
Joseph, you can stay.
You shall not bother us.
Is that not so, Isabella?
He is monstrous.
Diabolical.
Possessed.
Help me, Nelly.
How goes your search
for a position?
It does not.
Edgar has forbidden it.
Hmm. Has he?
Once again,
my despair seems to be
your good fortune, Nelly.
I hope it soothes you
to blame me.
I told you
they would not read it.
Well, the letter
was not shocking enough,
or Nelly would've shown them.
I thought
it was quite harrowing.
It could not have been,
or they would respond.
Well, if you doubt
my competence,
then why don't you
write a letter?
Oh, no... You can't.
Hmm.
Write another...
to Cathy directly.
And then you
will be nice to me.
Then I will be
very nice to you.
It has been too long.
I must see Catherine.
And how will she respect you
if you relent now?
Think what permissions you
will grant if you comfort her.
It would be nothing short
of an endorsement.
You must not see her.
Hold fast.
Show her you will not bend.
It is more important than ever
now Heathcliff has returned.
Heathcliff has returned?
Isabella has written.
They are at the Heights.
She wishes most fervently
to see you.
Well, she can wish all she
wants, but it is in vain.
Tell her she can go hang
for all I care,
and tell my wife
to pull herself together.
I will have order
in this house again.
How many more weeks of this
must we all endure?
It is not good for you.
It is not good for the baby.
-The baby is gone.
-When?
Have you bled?
No.
If you have not bled,
then the baby is fine.
If you say so.
Stop it now, Cathy,
or you will be in danger
of losing Edgar's
affection forever.
Heathcliff is gone.
You must accept it.
Mrs. Heathcliff's fortune
is in London, and--
Do not call her that.
-It is her name.
-It is my name.
I named him. He is mine.
Oh, shut up. It's Catherine.
Oh, Nelly. What do you want?
What is this?
It's nothing.
She has been insolent.
This is monstrous.
Isabella, come at once.
Isabella, stay.
Heathcliff,
let the poor thing go.
Can't you see
she must hate you?
Aye.
She says so 100 times a day.
And yet...
Isabella, if I leave you alone
for half a day,
won't you come sighing
and wheedling back to me?
She's a funny creature, Nelly.
No brutality disgusts her.
No, I must suppose she has
an innate admiration of it.
So tell Catherine
I have finally found
my match in degradation.
Look.
I will tell her no such thing.
I want no part
of whatever this is.
For God's sake, Heathcliff.
Isabella,
let me take you home.
Would you like to come home?
Nelly, I am home.
Write to Cathy again.
She cannot ignore me forever.
Have any letters
come for me, Nelly?
None at all.
Cathy,
let us call a truce now.
For this silence
will kill us both.
I will wait for you every day
and every night.
Why do you not respond?
I love you. I love you.
I love you.
Cathy!
Cathy, why did you do it?
I am sorry.
Stop it. Stop it.
It is enough now.
Enough. Get out of bed.
I fear I cannot.
You can.
You can,
you selfish, wicked creature.
You can.
I will not stand for
this grotesque performance
a moment longer.
You are revolting.
You are both revolting.
Get out of bed.
Ah, Nelly has
played traitor again.
Nelly is my hidden enemy.
What the devil is it?
"Theatrics," Nelly? These are
the signs of septicemia.
She said the baby died
some time ago.
I thought it was a pretense.
"A pretense"?
Then you are a torturer.
For God's sake.
Sir.
I cannot imagine what
hatred has been in your heart
for you to allow this, but
I will not have you near her.
Get out. Now. Go.
Go!
Where's the doctor?
No, no.
No, don't go.
Please, Nelly.
I think I must.
Whatever it was,
I'm sure you did not mean it.
Oh...
But I think I did.
I won't tell.
Nelly...
Yes?
Heathcliff... Heathcliff...
I said you would kill me.
Look.
No, no, no.
No, you will be well
by tomorrow.
Hmm? Hmm?
Think of the number of times
you have claimed to be dying.
Thousands at least.
I've never believed you.
And I won't today.
You are fine.
You will be fine.
I'm sorry.
Get off me. I'll kill you.
Heathcliff, do not.
You do not want to see...
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
Heathcliff...
What?
Cathy? Cathy?
Wha...
Get the doctor!
For God's sake,
somebody get the doctor!
You are all right.
You are fine.
My love, my love.
My darling pain.
Only do not go. No.
No, no, do not go.
It is unutterable.
I cannot live without my life.
I cannot live without my soul.
You... You said I killed you.
Haunt me then.
Be with me always.
Take any form.
Drive me mad.
Only please do not leave me
in this abyss
where I cannot find you.
Heathcliff...
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Don't ever be sorry
for me, Cathy.
For I would do it
again and again.
Then we're doomed.
What can I do?
Nothing.
Just stay with me.
Cathy?
Cathy, are you awake?
Catherine Earnshaw...
I will love you
until the day that I die...
and forever after.